嘿 我钓到了
Hey! I got something!
收线
Reel it in.
像是条200磅的马林鱼
Man, feels like a 200-pound marlin.
钓到什么了
What did we catch?
不管是什么 反正肯定很大
Whatever it is, it's big.
NCIS 新奥尔良S03 E12
早上好 NCIS探员们
Good morning, fellow NCIS agents.
-嗯哼 -早上好
- Uh-huh. - Good morning.
天啊
Geez.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我不是第一次入职了
Not my first rodeo.
新人第一天上班总会被戏弄的
Day one on the job, newbie always gets hazed.
椅子坏了 桌子里有老鼠
Broken chair, rats in the desk
奶精里有泻药
Laxatives in the creamer.
你在FBI的同事都是反社会啊
What kind of sociopaths did you work with at FBI?
妹子 在贩毒集团的案子结束后
Girl, after everything that went down with the cartel,
我们要做好几天的文书工作
we got paperwork for days.
没人有空来捉弄你
Nobody got time for hazing.
但要恭喜你通过了FLETC的训练
Congrats getting through FLETC, though.
联邦执法培训中心
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
Gregorio
Gregorio!
耶
Yeah.
你真该看看自己的表情
You should have seen your face.
我们把你骗得那么好
Yeah, we got you so good.
NCIS特别探员Gregorio
NCIS Special Agent Gregorio,
我们用新奥尔良山核桃派切片
we'd like to officially welcome you to our team,
正式欢迎你加入我们团队
to the city, with a special slice
也欢迎来到这座城市
of New Orleans pecan pie.
我很感谢
I appreciate it.
还有以后记住 我讨厌惊喜
And for future reference, I hate surprises.
你讨厌乐趣
So you hate fun.
惊喜不是乐趣
Surprises aren't fun.
如果我不能嗅出惊喜
And I'm not much of an agent
我就不能算是一名探员
if I can't sniff out a surprise.
这个嘛 我们还有一个惊喜给你
Well, we got one more for you.
我们知道 你有多想戴上这个
We know how badly you've wanted to wear one of these,
-所以我们给你... -拜托 别说
- so we got you... - Please, don't say...
-帽子 -帽子
- ...a hat. - ...a hat.
-NCIS团队的官方帽子 -哇哦
- Official NCIS team hat. - Whoo-hoo.
-我一定要戴吗 -当然
- Do I have to? - Yes.
现在就戴上
Put it on right now.
-让我们看看 -很漂亮
- Let me see. Yeah. - Oh, that's nice.
哦 看看这喜悦之情
Oh, look at the happiness
从帽子里溢出来了
pouring out of the hat.
我觉得自己做了件错事
I think I made a mistake.
工作时间到
Time for work.
Jay Nielsen上尉的尸体
The body of Lieutenant Jay Nielsen was just
刚在墨西哥湾被钓上来
fished out of the Gulf.
这会儿已经在Lorreta的解剖台上了
Landing on Loretta's table as we speak.
Sonja 你跟我去验尸房
Sonja, you're with me at the morgue.
Lasalle和Gregorio
Lasalle and Gregorio,
去Nielsen上尉最近去过的地方调查
dig into Lieutenant Nielsen's recent whereabouts.
查出他怎么最终死在了水里
Find out how he ended up in the drink.
哦 你这个小探员
Oh, you, a little agent.
那好 我去联系
All right, so I'll contact
他的指挥官和亲人
his commanding officer, next of kin.
你去调查他的财政情况和通话记录
You take his financials and phone records.
怎么了
What?
我牙齿里有东西吗
Do I have something in my teeth?
-你在看什么 -没什么
- What are you looking at? - No.
Pride不在时 我资历最深
I'm ranking agent when Pride's not around,
应该是我发号施令才对
so I kind of call the shots.
得了吧 你是认真的吗
Oh, stop. Are you for real?
我知道你以前在FBI地位很高
I know you were a big deal in the FBI,
但在这儿你是新人 得服从团队规矩
but you're the newbie here, so gotta follow team rules.
啊 所以是我逾越规矩了么
Ah. So, uh, I jump on the paper trail?
是的 我去打电话
Yeah, and I'll make the phone calls.
行
Okay.
顺便说一句 帽子不错
That hat looks good, by the way.
有什么发现吗 Loretta
What have we got here, Loretta?
看上去像是
Something out of a Salvador Dali painting,
萨瓦多尔达利的画
it would seem.
超现实主义画家
哇 我说
Wow! Shoot.
这不是鱼造成的吧
Um, guessing a fish didn't do that?
肯定不是
Most definitely not.
Nielsen上尉死于热冲击
Lieutenant Nielsen died of thermal shock.
由于某种很强的热量
His heart, lungs, bones literally melted
他的心脏 肺 骨头都熔化了
by some intense, concentrated heat.
哦 那个...
Ugh. Well, uh...
Nielsen在菲律宾驻扎了
Nielsen was stationed in the Philippines
六个月 两天前回来的
for six months, got back two days ago.
这次回家还真是不容易
This is a rough homecoming.
十分不容易 根据
Mm, very rough, and judging by
他脸上的瘀伤
the bruising on his face
和手上的防卫伤判断
and defensive wounds on his hands,
上尉当时打架是拼了命的
our lieutenant was in the fight of his life.
有可能是和烧伤他胸口的人打斗
Presumably with the person who burned in his chest?
嘿
Hey, uh,
Tammy和Lasalle查到了
Tammy and Lasalle got
Nielsen最后被看到的地方
Nielsen's last-known whereabouts.
在奥尔良码头 他们现在在去的路上
Orleans Marina. They're headed there now.
让他们去的时候带上你
Have 'em pick you up on their way.
去吧 了解情况
Go. Learn things.
知道是什么造成的伤害吗
Any idea what caused the damage?
不知道
No.
而且查明的可能性不大
And the chances of finding out aren't favorable.
由于Sebastian在进行NCIS训练
With Sebastian getting his NCIS shield,
我只有一帮换来换去的临时助手
I get a revolving door of temps.
赶紧交差来了
Drop it like it's hot.
我测试了你送来的尸体样本 Wade医生
I tested the flesh sample you sent in, Doc Wade.
这家伙被火烧了
Dude was torched.
这家伙有名字的 Nielsen上尉
The dude has a name-- Lieutenant Nielsen.
好吧 Nielsen上尉
Right, Lieutenant Nielsen.
天啊 这太狠了
Oh, man, that is gnarly.
Pride探员
Agent Pride,
认识下我们实验室技术人员 Claire Belcher
meet our lab technician, Claire Belcher.
她刚从新奥尔良科技学院毕业
She's just graduated from New Orleans Technical College.
这是她的第一份工作
This is her first job.
我以前从没看到过这样的东西
I have never seen anything like that before.
很高兴见到你 Belcher女士
Glad to meet you, Ms. Belcher.
你说Nielsen上尉被火烧了
You were saying Lieutenant Nielsen was torched.
知道是什么造成的吗
Any idea by what?
我想说 哇哦
I mean... wow.
他像是被熔化了
Like, he got melted.
是的 我们想知道是什么造成的
Yes. And we were wondering what did it.
我觉得...
I think, you know...
我想Sebastian了
I miss Sebastian.
-我知道为什么了 -嗯哼
- I see why. - Mm-hmm.
呃 我会联系FLETC
Uh, I'll reach out to FLETC,
把验尸报告给Sebastian
get Sebastian the autopsy report.
看他能否帮我们缩小凶器的范围
See if he can help us narrow in on the murder weapon.
你跟他谈的时候 让他打电话给我
When you talk to him, have him call me.
我很担心他
He's got me worried.
俯卧撑和障碍训练真的不是他的长项
Push-ups and obstacle courses aren't really his forte.
我会的 但我确信他肯定没事 Loretta
I will, but I'm sure he's doing just fine, Loretta.
加油 Lund 上 上 上
Come on, Lund, move, move, move!
行动
Let's go!
我只是... 你知道战逃反应吗
I just... You know “fight or flight”?
指人在高压下，大脑调动身体作出攻击或逃跑的应激反应
其实还有第三种应激反应 叫"僵住"
Well, there's a third stress response-- it's called “freeze”"
这碰巧就是我正在经历的
And it's what I happen to be experiencing right now.
闭嘴 去敲铃铛
Shut up and ring the bell!
我只是 我看不出这个训练
I just... I don't see the practical application
有什么实际意义 长官
of this exercise, sir.
我是说 在真实场景中
I mean, in what real-world scenario
我会需要爬绳子吗
would I ever have to scale a rope, you know?
比如说 我要是在一艘海盗船上
Like, if I'm on a pirate ship?
等等 你要 要做什么
Wait, what-what are you doing?
这里没有位置了
There's no room at the inn!
两个人太挤了 你知道我的意思吗
Two's a crowd, you know what I mean?
天啊
Oh, God.
你在干什么 你在 呃
What are you doing? What... Uh.
等等
Wait...
等等 等等 把它放回来
Wait, wait, wait. Put that back.
敲响铃铛
Ring the bell!
好了 好了 我做到了
Okay. Okay, I did it.
我敲了 拜托快把垫子放回去吧
I did it, now put the pad back, please.
我做到了
I did it.
如果完成不了 你就会摔断脚踝
You would have broken your ankle if you hadn't.
恐惧只能帮你到这 Lund
Fear only gets you so far, Lund.
如果你想当一名探员 最好能找到另一种方法
You want to make agent, you better find another way
来激励你爬上绳子
to motivate your butt up that rope.
Nielsen上尉的妻子说 他早早结束巡航回来
Lieutenant Nielsen's wife said he came home early from tour
为了带她参加在他们船上举行的周年航行
to take her on an anniversary cruise on their boat.
家住什里夫波特市 昨天开车过来做准备
Lives in Shreveport, drove down yesterday to prep.
接着就听到伤亡援助电话处上门的消息
Next thing she knows, CACO's at her door.
留给她的是心碎
She's left with a broken heart
而他的丈夫是真的被烧死了
while her husband was literally melted away.
-女士优先 -哦 不
- Ladies first. - Oh, no.
你是资深探员 当然要你先
You're senior ranking agent. By all means.
话是没错 但我也是一名绅士
Well, that's true. But I'm also a gentleman,
所以您先请
so after you.
-哦 不 我... -听着 女士们
- Oh, no, I... - Look, ladies,
你们都很漂亮 快走吧
you're both pretty-- let's go.
没有鸟屎 没有盐矿床
No bird poop, no salt deposits.
没有藤壶堆积
No barnacle buildup.
考虑到这艘船已经在这里停靠了六个月
Considering this boat's been sitting here for six months,
保持得还真好啊
it's in dang good shape.
好过头了 要检查检查
Too good. Check it.
你看到了这层新漆底下的黑点了吗
You see these black spots under this fresh coat of paint?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
这是蛋白质烟雾损伤
It's protein smoke damage.
我在ATF的在纵火案中见到过
Used to see it in arson cases with ATF.
当人身上着火的时候 脂肪和油脂
When the body catches fire, the fats and oils
就会化为烟并覆盖所有东西
turn into smoke and coat everything.
所以这些烟尘很有可能是
So this soot could be leftover residue
上尉胸口燃烧后的残留物吗
from our lieutenant's burning chest?
而且不管是谁烧伤了他
And it looks like whoever torched him
都曾试图刷漆 掩盖证据
tried to paint over the evidence
并清理了这艘船
and clean up the boat.
我想我们找到案发现场了
Think we might have just found our crime scene.
我有发现 你们需要过来看看
I got something y'all need to see.
Nielsen夫人说上尉是唯一一个
Mrs. Nielsen said the lieutenant was the only one
可以上船的人
who had access to the boat,
但我觉得她错了
but I think she was wrong.
看看这个
Look at this.
根据计时表来看
According to the hour meter,
在过去的六个月里
there's five trips, 12 hours each,
有五趟出行 每次12个小时
over the last six months
当时上尉是被派驻海外
while the lieutenant was stationed overseas.
有其他人在使用这艘船
Someone else was using the boat.
跟杀害他的是同一个人吗
The same someone who killed him?
上尉偶然发现了嫌疑人
The lieutenant stumbles on the suspect,
嫌疑人用喷枪烧伤了他 并把他丢进海湾
who proceeds to blowtorch him, dump him in the Gulf.
这么看来 很冷血啊
Now, that's cold-blooded.
不管罪犯用这艘船做了什么
Well, whatever the perp was using the boat for,
他都觉得这件事值得他杀人
he thought it was worth killing over.
我正在调出GPS行程记录
I'm pulling up the GPS trip history,
重播最后一次行程
replaying the last one.
这艘船开到石油钻塔去做什么
What was the boat doing out at an oil rig?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是这个偷船贼
But seeing as our boat thief
愿意用谋杀来掩盖他的行迹
was willing to murder to cover his tracks,
就不会是什么好事
it can't be good.
Apolis五号石油钻塔 离海岸200英里
Apolis oil rig 5. 200 miles off the coast.
每天运输2500桶原油
Pumps 2,500 barrels of crude a day.
这与海军上尉谋杀案有什么联系
What has it got to do with the murder of a Navy lieutenant?
还不清楚 但杀害Nielsen上尉的凶手
Well, no idea, but Lieutenant Nielsen's killer
偷了他的船 并在他被派驻海外期间
took his stolen boat out to that rig five times
五次去油塔
while he was stationed overseas.
长途用的油箱 增压的发动机
Long distance fuel bladders, super charged engine.
绝对是出行的最佳轮船
It's the perfect vessel for the journey.
现在就不是了 因为Nielsen撞见了嫌疑人
Not so perfect once Nielsen surprised the suspect,
并因此被点燃 然后抛尸在墨西哥湾
got lit up for his trouble and dumped in the Gulf.
一个拥有喷枪的凶手
A torch-wielding killer,
一艘被偷的船和一个海上石油钻塔
a stolen boat and an offshore oil rig.
有什么联系
What's the connection?
嗨 抱歉 电话回晚了
Hey. Uh, sorry it took me a little bit to call you back.
我一直在忙别的事儿
I've been... otherwise engaged.
我猜到了 训练情况还好吗
I bet. Training going okay?
哦 很好 很好 不能更好了
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah. Couldn't be better.
你知道的 结交一生的朋友
Uh, you know. Making life-long friends.
走上人生的巅峰 还是老一套
Achieving personal bests. The usual.
你有时间看我们发给你的尸检报告么
You find time to look at the autopsy report we sent?
有 有 我看了 而且我想我知道
Yeah, yeah. I did, and I-I think I know
Nielsen上尉是被什么杀害的
what killed Lieutenant Nielsen.
一切都还好吗 Sebastian
Everything okay, Sebastian?
当然了 很好 都很好
Oh, sure. Yeah. All good.
那你为什么这么小声
So why are you so whispery?
我只是 严格来说 我是不可以
I just... I'm not technically allowed
现在打电话的 但是 这
to be on my phone right now, but, um... it's...
这太酷了 所以听着
it's totally cool. So listen.
根据受害者身上残留的
I, uh, based on the chemical residue
化学物质 我认为
on the victim's body, I think
你们要找的凶器是一种深海用的
that your murder weapon was a deep-sea,
燃烧氧的焊接喷枪
oxy-fueled welding torch.
需要有美国焊工联盟的证明
Now, you need certification from the American Welders Union
才能持有 并操作它
to own and... and operate one.
我们会检查他们的数据库
We check their database,
或许能筛选一份
might be able to compile a list
嫌疑人名单 干得好 Sebastian
of suspects. Good work, Sebastian.
好的 谢谢 我得挂了
Okay. Thanks. I got to go.
确定一切都还好吗 Sebastian
Sure it's going okay, Sebastian?
不 什么 哦 好 好
No. What? Oh, yeah, yeah.
不 很好 一切都非常棒
No. It's great. Uh, everything's awesome.
说实话 我在这里很愉快
To be honest, I'm having a great time,
不能再好了 所以
and it couldn't be better, so...
混蛋 Lund 我说了不许打电话
Damn it, Lund! I said no cell phones!
哦 好的 好吧
Oh. Okay, all right.
他看上去很友善
He seems friendly.
不 那是特别探员Perkins
No. That's Special Agent Perkins.
我在FLETC的第一天 就见他弄哭了一名前海军陆战队员
I saw him make a former Marine cry on my first day at FLETC.
幸运的是 我只需要上周末课程
Luckily, I only had to do the weekend course,
而且我勉强通过了那个课程
and I barely made it through that one.
祝Sebastian好运吧
So, Sebastian's toast.
他体能上的不足 他都会从精神上弥补
Well, what he lacks in strength, he makes up for in spirit.
我可以跟你赌任何东西 他会通过的
I'll bet you anything he makes it through.
打赌的事以后再说吧
Save the bets for later.
Chris Gregorio 去Apolis总部 去看看他们
Chris, Gregorio, get to Apolis HQ. See if they got
是否知道 那艘船在他们的油塔附近做什么
any idea what that boat was doing out by their rig.
我在焊工联盟有个老朋友
I got an old friend at the Welders Union,
应该可以帮我们获取数据库权限
should be able to get us access to their database.
帮不了你们 没人报告说
Can't help you. Haven't heard one word
5号钻井有快艇接近过
about a boat near rig 5.
它多次穿过了你们的安全范围
It crossed your safety perimeter multiple times.
你们难道没有保安在那儿
Don't you have security in place
监控周边船只吗
to monitor vessels from doing that?
你是想知道我怎么管理公司
You interested in how I run my company
还是想知道我有没有看到那艘快艇
or whether I saw this boat?
没事 妈妈 我来解释
It's all right, Mom. I'll explain.
当指标下降 石油市场触底时
When the indexes fell and the oil market bottomed out,
我们被迫在财政方面做了艰难的决定
we were forced to make some hard fiscal decisions.
我们不得不取消了安保 就这么简单
We had to cut security, plain and simple.
花10万美元拿到工商管理硕士学位 现在话都不会说了
$100,000 for an MBA and he's speaking gibberish.
你们有24个人在国际水域
You got 24 men out there in international waters
就没人照看他们一下么
and no one looking out for them?
我们不是英国石油公司 我们只是个家族企业
We're not BP. we're a family business.
目前世界第四大上下游一体化经营的跨国石油公司
泵机价格下跌以后 我们能做的
And with prices falling at the pumps, we either had to start
要么减少轮班 要么减少安保人员
cutting shifts or cut security personnel.
该死
Damn it.
这周围遭到了破坏
These perimeter breaches,
这些标识对应我们油管泄漏的地方
they correspond with leaks to our pipeline.
-泄漏 -六个月前
- Leaks? - Six months back,
5号钻井突然开始出现泄漏情况
puncture-leaks start popping up around rig 5.
我们不得不关闭石油生产 直到把它们焊好
Had to shut down oil production till we welded them up.
Nielsen上尉是被深海焊枪杀死的
Lieutenant Nielsen was killed by a deep-sea welding torch.
也许那个焊枪原本有别的用途
Maybe it was intended for something else.
比如在管道上烧几个洞
Like making holes in the pipeline.
能想到有谁会做这种事吗
Any idea who would want to do something like this?
我们的任何竞争对手都会这样做
Just about every one of our competitors.
没错 不过我们的工程师们确定
Yes, except our engineers determined those leaks
管道上的那些洞都是正常磨损导致的
to be normal wear and tear to our pipeline.
别天真了 Elliot 我们一直在亏损
Don't be so naive, Elliot. We're all hurting here.
每次我们关闭一个油井
Every time we shut down a rig,
沿海地区的油价就会飙升
oil prices spike across the seaboard.
企业的蓄意破坏 我感觉就像回到了华盛顿
Corporate sabotage. I feel like I'm back in D.C.
这和华盛顿无关 石油生意就是很残酷的
This may not be Washington, but oil's a cutthroat business.
你们需要什么来查清整件事
What do you need to get to the bottom of this?
帮我们确认那艘快艇上凶手的身份
Help us I.D. the killer on that boat.
如果有人看到什么
Anybody saw something, it'd be
那人就一定在钻井平台上
one of those men out on that rig.
那我们就得去那个平台了
Then we'll need to get on that rig.
好的 我联系到一架直升机
Well, I got a helo
一小时后飞过去换班
taking a shift out in an hour.
如果你们想去 还有一个空位
One seat left if you want it.
-我去 -我去
- I'll take it. - I'll take it.
石头剪刀布
Rock-paper-scissors?
得了 这是浪费时间
All right. Ah, it's a waste of time.
我们都不会坐上那个座位
We're not getting on that seat anyway.
那谁会
Well, who is?
第一次来 是不是
First time out, huh?
你知道我在哪能找到钻井经理吗
You know where I can find the rig manager?
跟上 我领你去
Keep up. I'll show you.
闻到了吗
Oh, yeah. Smell that?
汽油味 体臭
Petrol, B.O.
还有甜蜜的海风
and the sweet ocean breeze.
拥抱它吧 地球上再没有地方跟这儿一样了
Embrace it. No place like it on Earth.
你做钻工多久了
How long you been roughnecking?
两年
Two years.
不过 这是我最后一次过来了
This is my last hitch, though.
是时候开始下一段旅途了 一个新世界
Time for the next part of my journey, a new frontier.
给 看看这个
Here. Check this out.
"心之所向包租公司"
“Your Heart's Desire Charters”.
我曾在安第斯山脉跋涉
I've trekked the Andes,
给横渡大西洋的货船导航
navigated transatlantic cargo ships,
拿到了学位 现在 我的飞行员执照也有了
got my degree, and now... my pilot's license.
还有你见过的那架
Plus the sweetest little twin engine Cessna
双引擎塞斯纳飞机
you've ever laid eyes on.
-印象深刻 -嗯
- Very impressive. - Mm.
我能不能自作主张地给你提点建议
Can I give you a piece of unsolicited advice?
你在这里 要把注意力放在工事上
While you're here, set your eyes on the work,
而不是看风景 钻井是个危险的地方
not the view. Rig's a dangerous place.
而且这里太远了 等医疗直升机飞过来
And it's remote. By the time the medevac gets here,
一切就都太迟了
it's always too late.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
那是你要找的人
There's your man.
记住
And remember,
留意钻井
eyes on the rig.
你肯定是Pride探员
You must be Agent Pride.
我是Hauser 很高兴你能过来
I'm Hauser. Glad to have you aboard.
谢谢
Thank you.
法人代表让我为你
Corporate told me to give you
提供你所需要的一切
access to whatever you need,
你让我往东 我不会往西
so, you say jump, I'll say how high.
非常感谢
I appreciate it.
我需要跟你的工作人员谈谈
I need to speak to your crew.
看看有没有人记得有艘快艇来过这里
See if any of them remember a boat that's been out here.
就在最近 几天前的晚上
Most recently, a couple nights back?
噢 我们这里有不少船只过来呢
Oh, we get a lot of boats out here.
你能不能说得更具体些
You... You want to be more specific?
45英尺超级运动快艇
The 45 foot Super Sport.
有人非法使用了它
Someone was using it illegally.
哦 船真漂亮 我猜
Oh. She's a beauty. I'm guessin' there's more
能把NCIS引过来
to the story than just some joyridin'
肯定不是飚船之类的
to bring NCIS out here.
一名海军上尉在船上被杀了
Navy lieutenant was murdered on it.
好吧 那我们 我们先跟平台人员谈谈吧
Okay. Well, let's, uh... let's talk to the floor hands first.
当然 Pride在夏天去过他叔叔的钻井平台干活儿
Of course Pride spent summers working on his uncle's oil rig.
这家伙还有什么没做过的事
What hasn't the guy done?
经过认证的全能型人才 所以他是老大
Certifiable Renaissance man. That's why he's the boss.
不过我才是你们要找的人
But this is why I'm the man.
为你们找到了一个上尉谋杀案的嫌疑人
Found you a suspect in the lieutenant's murder.
Pride的联络有回音了
Pride's connection paid off.
我们进入了焊工联盟的数据库
We got us access to the Welders Union database.
我们一直在交叉对比
We've been combing through it, cross-referencing
Nielsen上尉的个人信息和数据库
with Lieutenant Nielsen's personal life.
Darren Meade 焊工联盟的正式会员
Darren Meade. Card-carrying member of the union,
Nielsen上尉的姐夫
Lieutenant Nielsen's brother-in-law.
他应该知道Nielsen在外出
Would have known Nielsen was on tour,
并且知道他的快艇没有人用
and known his boat was available.
根据联盟的记录
And according to union records,
他在Nielsen被杀的早晨
he refilled an oxygenized torch-tank
给焊枪燃料箱补充了一个富氧燃料罐
the morning of Nielsen's murder.
Darren Meade现在在哪儿
Where's Darren Meade now?
问到点上了
Well, that's the kicker.
Darren在钻井上工作
Darren works the rigs for a living.
他刚开始十天的轮班
He just cycled into a ten-day shift.
-猜猜他在哪儿 -Apolis的5号钻井平台
- Guess where. - Apolis oil rig 5.
Pride跟凶手一起在钻井平台上 而他并不知道
Pride's on the rig with the killer, and doesn't know it?
离海岸200英里远 他的手机也没信号
200 miles off the coast. He ain't got cell reception either.
我给油井的座机打电话
I'll call the rig's sat line.
我们得警告他
We got to warn him.
你确定之前没看到一个运动快艇
You sure you didn't see a Super Sport?
没有 警官
No, sir.
没看见不能说看见了
Can't say I seen it.
您刚才说它什么时间来过
When did you say it was here?
几天前的一个晚上 十一点左右
Around 11:00 p.m. Couple nights back.
经理说你当时正在上夜班
Manager said you were working the swing shift.
在这个有利位置 你的视野应该会很清楚
From this vantage point, you would've had a clear view.
没错
Yeah.
我看得很清楚
I would've.
可我当时什么都没看到
But I didn't see nothing.
脖子上的淤青很严重啊 怎么弄的
Nasty bruise you got on your neck. What happened?
不小心撞到甲板下面的管道了
Ran into a water pipe below deck.
管道碰巧是手指形状的么
Pipe happened to be hand shaped?
在Apolis 什么形状的管道都有
Got all kinds of pipes on Apolis.
根据个人记录
According to personnel records,
你是这钻井上唯一
you're the only welder on this rig
有权使用焊枪的焊工
authorized to use that torch.
我想是的
I guess that's true.
跟你有关吗
What's it to you?
你老板说前两周
Well, your boss says you've been working repairs
你一直在负责维修
the last two weeks.
我猜如果我检查两晚前的
Assuming that if I check the shift logs
交班记录 我能找到你的名字
two nights back, I'd find you.
你为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
因为你一直在对我说谎
'Cause you've been lying to me.
这只是演习
This is just a drill.
所有工作人员去食堂大厅报到
All crew members report to the mess hall.
重复 所有工作人员去食堂大厅进行安全检查
I repeat, all crew to the mess hall for a safety check.
你要把所有人都支走
You stashing away the crew
直到我们想出解决办法为止吗
till we figure out how to play this?
现在只有一种解决办法
There's only one way to play this.
在那家伙找到救生艇
Take care of this guy before he gets
或传话出去以前 干掉他
to one of those lifeboats, or gets word off this rig.
我已经拿到他的枪 干掉他会简单许多
It should be easier now that I got his gun.
如果当时你冷静一点 而不是突然慌张
Yeah. It'd be easier if you'd played it cool
一切会更简单
instead of going all pyro.
我们现在都找不到他了
We can't even find him.
没得选啊 他盯上我们了
No choice. He was onto us.
所以呢 我们现在要杀警察了吗
So what? We're killin' a cop now?
无服务
我很不情愿这么做
I get no pleasure from it,
但必要时候我们必须为了自己这样做 对吧
but we do what we have to to take care of our own. Right?
-我们杀的人越来越多了 -嘿 我们这么做
- Bodies are starting to stack up. - Hey, we got into this
就是为了给家里
to make some money,
多弄些钱
provide for our families.
我可不想因此进监狱 你想吗
I'm not about to go to prison for it. Are you?
给他一枪 把尸体扔下去
Put a bullet in him, toss him over.
沉降流会让他的尸体
The downwellings out here will take his body
直接沉到海底
right to the ocean floor.
没人会再见到他
Nobody will ever see it again.
只是个钻井事故罢了
Just be another rig accident.
这人在安全演习的时候慌了 直接掉进海里
Guy panicked during a safety drill, fell overboard.
你凭什么觉得他们会买账
What makes you think they'll buy that?
因为我有两个目击证人
'Cause I got two witnesses
来证实我说的话
to back up my story.
没进展么
I take it no luck?
Apolis总部和钻井彻底失去联系了
Apolis HQ lost all communications to the rig.
他们正在努力弄清楚发生了什么
They're scrambling to figure out what's going on.
你从海岸警卫队那里有什么好消息吗
You do any better with the Coast Guard?
正在调动他们距离最近的小型武装快艇 但是
Redirecting their nearest cutter-- it'll be three,
也得三四个小时才能抵达钻井
four hours before the boat reaches that rig.
所以我们根本没办法警告Pride
So we got no way of warning Pride
他正和一个凶手呆在一起
he's out there with a killer.
是多个凶手 调出了谋杀案那晚
Killers, plural. Dumped Darren's phone records
Darren的通话记录
from the night of the murder.
他和Apolis的两名雇员
He was in touch with two Apolis employees--
Jackson Hauser和Lyle Peterson联系过
Jackson Hauser and Lyle Peterson.
我检查了他们的短信 能看出其中两个人
Yeah, I checked their texts-- it appears that two of them
在上尉被烧死的当晚在快艇上
was on the lieutenant's boat the night he got torched.
所以Pride不止和一个凶手在一起 而是三个
So Pride's not with one killer, he's with three?
其中一个还是经过训练的
And a trained one at that.
Hauser以前是个步兵 在阿富汗打过仗
Hauser's ex-infantry, fought in Afghanistan.
他们负责给管道打洞
These guys put holes in that pipeline.
他们很有可能想在Pride揭发他们之前
There's a good chance they'll want to take Pride out
-干掉他 -我们没时间
- before he blows the whistle. - And we don't have time to wait
等海岸警卫队的快艇到那儿了
for the Coast Guard cutter to get there.
去把他们召回
Let's call them back,
-看他们能不能用直升机送我们过去 -好
- see if they'll chopper us out. - All right.
Patton和Sonja继续尝试
Patton, Sonja, keep trying
和钻井重新取得联系
to reestablish connection with the rig.
必要时候给Sebastian打电话
Call Sebastian if you have to.
-不惜一切代价 -现在就办
- Do whatever it takes. - On it.
Gregorio 你跟我来
Gregorio, you're with me.
挺有Pride的样子啊 Lasalle
Not a bad Pride impression, Lasalle.
不过我还是更喜欢真的那个
I still prefer the real thing, though.
相信我 我也是 我们去找他
Trust me, so do I. Let's go get him.
哦 又是美好的一天
Oh, just another day in paradise.
嘿 如果你在找食堂的话 兄弟
Hey, if you're looking for the mess hall, my man,
-这里可不是 -我是个联邦探员
- this ain't it. - I'm a federal agent.
在这个钻井上 有人想杀我
There are men on this rig who are trying to kill me.
我需要对外通信
I need to get a line out.
整个系统都是离线的
The whole system's offline.
传感器 无线电 卫星通信 所有都是
Sensors, radio, satcom, all of it.
还有什么办法能从这里发出消息吗
Is there any other way to get a message off this thing?
在钻井地下室有个无线电发射器
There's a distress beacon in the rig cellar--
你可以用摩尔斯电码发求救信号
you can send an SOS using Morse code.
那哥们刚才不是在开枪打我们吧
That dude did not just shoot at us!
-你还好吗 -我还好
- You okay? - Yeah, I'm okay.
我们得离开这里 快走
All right, we got to get out of here. Come on.
-趁他们还没闯进来... -我当时说
- Before they bust in... - This is not what I meant
希望能在旅途的最后听到嘭的响声
when I said I wanted to go out with a bang
可不是指这个
on my last tour.
嘿
Hey.
拿着 把水喝了
Here you go, drink that.
慢点儿喝
Slow.
你能告诉我为什么这几个修理工想杀你吗
You want to tell me why those grease monkeys want you dead?
他们杀了一位海军 而我是不会让他们逍遥法外的
They killed a Navy sailor, and I'm not gonna let them get away with it.
如果你要抓这些坏蛋 我帮你
If you're gonna take out those fools, I'm with you.
慢着 慢着
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你拿它干嘛
What are you gonna do with that?
在我长大的地方
Where I grew up,
如果有人打了你 你要打回去
if someone takes a swing at you, you swing back.
好吧 这是个值得尊敬的风俗 不过
Okay, all right, that's an honorable code, but...
面对装有11发子弹的SIG Sauer手枪
a wrench won't do any good against a SIG Sauer
一个扳手可不占什么优势
with 11 rounds left in the magazine.
那你有什么好办法
Well, what do you propose, then?
你带我去求无线电发射器那里
You take me to those signal beacons.
我给我的团队发信息 叫后援
I'll get word to my team, get backup.
我们要拿下他们
We'll take these guys down.
嘿 我不需要你来代表我
Hey, I'm not looking to get deputized here.
我也不怎么喜欢"我们"这个词 好吗
And I'm not much for “we,” okay?
所以你做你的 我做我的
So you do you and I'll do me.
也许我也能找到一把信号枪
Maybe find another one of those flare guns.
Bonnie Bonnie 对吧
Bonnie. Bonnie, right?
-对 -听着 我需要你
- Yeah. - Okay, listen, I need you
按照我说的去做
to do what I tell you to do.
在食堂里有20个无辜的人
There are 20 innocent people up in that commissary.
如果我们进行枪战 有人打中了油箱
We get into a shoot out, someone hits a fuel tank,
那他们的死就有我们的责任
their deaths are gonna be on us.
我们需要合作
We got to do our part,
而不是直接冲进枪林弹雨
and running into a hail of bullets isn't it.
所以你带我去无线电发射器那里
So are you gonna show me where those beacons are,
还是我自己去找
or do I have to find them myself?
你最好有一个厉害的团队
You better have one hell of a cavalry.
三个都是国内最好的探员
Three of the best agents in the country.
三个
Three?
三个人么
As in three people?
暂时 过几周会有第四个
For now. Couple weeks I'll have a fourth--
但他得通过训练
he's got to get through training.
-天啊 -快 我们走
- Oh, God. - Come on, let's go.
好吧
All right.
Sebastian
Sebastian!
哦 抱歉 大伙
Oh. Sorry, guys.
哦 哦 别打了 别打了
Ow, ow, cut it out, cut it out, ow, ow.
我说过不能带电话 Lund
I said no more cell phones, Lund.
你害死了自己 还有你的队友
You got yourself killed, and your team, too!
-我可以解释的 -不 你不行 因为你已经死了
- I can explain. - No, you can't, because you are dead.
-死人是不会说话的 -是 但重点是
- Dead men do not talk. - Yeah, but the point is
我队友一直给我打电话 我 我不能
my team keeps calling me, and I-I can't...
总统跟你打电话又怎样
I don't care if the president of the United States is calling you.
我再发现你打电话 你就完了
I catch you on that phone again, you're done.
懂了不
Got it?!
把手机拿开
Put it away!
进去再来一次
Get in there and start over.
走
Go!
哪边
Which way?
-哦 完了 -咋了
- Aw, man. - What?
一直在冲击
The hits keep comin'.
太多钻机液被泵进来了
Too much drill fluid's being pumped in.
-钻井过度负载了 -有多糟糕
- It's overstressing the well. - How bad are we talking?
像"天启四骑士"那么糟糕
Like “Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse” bad.
出自圣经，指人类的四大灾祸：战争、瘟疫、饥荒、死亡
咱们得赶紧离开这里
We got to get out of here right now.
等等 Bonnie 等等
Whoa, whoa, Bonnie, no, no, we...
我们还得去信号塔
we still have to get to the signal beacons,
-警告我的团队 警告所有人 -好 行
- warn my team, warn everybody. - Okay, fine,
但是我们得快点了
but we got to hurry up.
这些仪表告诉我
These gauges are telling me
平台就要爆炸了
this rig's gonna blow.
这边
This way.
这个平台可以说是一个巨型的无线信号接收器
This rig is basically one giant Wi-Fi receiver.
没道理我连接不上啊
There's no good reason why I can't connect.
不想承认这一点
Hate to admit it,
但是我需要Sebastian的帮助
but I can use an assist from Sebastian.
我已经给他打过十几个电话了
Well, I've called him, like, ten times.
甚至还跟训练员留了言
I even left word with the training officer.
还是没回应
Still nothing.
这是 这是啥
What the... what is that?
来自这个平台
It's coming from the rig.
有人用摩斯码从平台发送信息
Someone's broadcasting Morse code off that rig.
我想我知道是谁
I think we know who.
-肯定是Pride -给我支笔
- Pride for the win. - Hand me a pen.
你从哪学的 在ATF么
Where'd you learn that, ATF?
-不是 是女童子军 -真的假的
- No. Girl Scouts. - Really?
高阶童子军
Senior level.
那就露一手吧 女童军
Well, let's hear it, troop leader.
平台就要 爆炸了
Rig is going to... blow.
离
Stay...
远点
away.
天啊 真希望是我的摩斯码退步了
God, I hope my Morse code is rusty.
有办法核实 NASA的公开资源
One way to check. NASA open source,
EO-1热能天线卫星
EO-1 thermal satellite.
好了 我刚刚对准了平台
Okay, I just aimed it at the rig.
哦 不 你的摩斯码没有退步
Oh, no, your Morse code ain't rusty.
那个红色的暴风云是碳氢化合物气体
That red storm cloud is all hydrocarbon gas.
意思是
Meaning...?
意思是 我们再不快一点的话
Meaning if we don't act fast,
我们看到的就是"深海地平线"了
we're looking Deepwater Horizon all over again.
位于美国路易斯安那州海岸约80公里的近海钻井油田。2010年4月20日发生爆炸并沉没，导致大规模的墨西哥湾原油污染。
我们还有多长时间
How long do we have?
没多长
Not long.
Pride正在那个随时都要爆炸的平台上
Pride's out there on that ticking time bomb of a rig
和三个凶手一起 你却把车开走了
with three killers, and you turn the car around?
把钥匙给我 我要要直升机
Give me the keys-- I'm getting on that chopper.
你哪儿也别想去
You're not going anywhere.
行 我开我自己的车
Fine, I'll take my own damn car.
你并不是老大 Lasalle
You're not the boss, Lasalle.
对 我不是 Pride才是
No, I'm not. Pride is.
不管他在这 还是在海岸线200英里外的地方
And whether he's right here or 200 miles off the coast,
我们都要听他的
we do what he says.
我不要
I don't...
现在 我们
Now, we all
都希望Pride回到他的办公桌上
want Pride back at his desk...
但是我们不能争吵
but we cannot do that by arguing.
Gregorio
Gregorio,
Lasalle是对的 平台周围爆炸气体的量太大了
Lasalle is right. With the amount
你们赶到那里
of HC gas around this rig, by the time you get there,
也是白费
it'll be too late.
那我也不能就坐在这
Well, I'm not just gonna
看着他炸飞
sit around and watch it blow.
Pride还指望着咱们呢
Pride is counting on us
找个办法救他
to find a way to save him
以及平台上的所有人
and the people on that rig.
那就开始工作吧
So let's get to work.
好吧 咱们怎么办
All right. Where do we start?
找到了
I got it.
跟着我 我展示给你们
Follow me. I'll show you.
我的系统一直在搜索
Kept my system scanning
从平台上发出的无线电信号
for radio signals to and from the rig.
有人在远程给平台上的液体泵发信号
Someone is remotely signaling the rig's fluid pumps,
往钻井里灌泥水 扰乱洞内压力
filling the well with mud, messing up the hole pressure.
这就解释了即将爆炸的原因
Explains why it's about to blow.
咱们的三个凶手在平台上
Well, our three killers are on the rig--
你是说他们还有同伙
you saying they have an accomplice?
某些会牺牲他们生命来掩盖踪迹的人
Someone willing to sacrifice their lives to cover their tracks.
我们能阻断信号么
Can we kill the signal?
得找出信号的来源
Got to find out where it's coming from.
同伙方面有头绪么
Any idea on the accomplice?
可能是生态恐怖分子
Well, it could be ecoterrorists.
他们之前瞄准过墨西哥湾的钻井平台
They've targeted the Gulf rigs before.
不可能 这三个嫌犯是彻头彻尾的油井修建工
No, the three suspects are lifelong roughnecks--
可不是树木热爱者
not exactly tree huggers.
也许是Apolis的竞争者之一
Hey, maybe one of Apolis's competitors.
有可能 但是我感觉这个凶手要更接近一些
Maybe, but I got a feeling this hits closer to home.
遥控那个平台只有两个方法
There's only two ways that rig's remotely operated--
要么是黑客 要么是
either by a hacker, or someone who has access
有权进入Apolis控制中心的人
to the control center at Apolis.
等一下
Wait.
为啥Apolis要炸掉他们自己的钻井平台
Why would Apolis want to blow up their own rig?
和他们竞争者相同的原因
Same reason their competitors would.
Patton 你能调出Apolis最近六个月的
Patton, can you pull Apolis's revenue streams
财政流水账单么
over the last six months on the go?
我们要去Apolis的总部
We're going to Apolis HQ.
这你还用问
Do you even have to ask?
行动吧 Gregorio
Your move, Gregorio.
好的
All right.
关掉15号
Close down 15.
还有油泥区分仪
And the mud-gas separator.
不 不管用
No, it's not working.
肯定有人远程控制了泵
Someone must be remotely overriding the pumps.
我们无法阻止
We can't stop them.
还得继续尝试
Got to keep trying.
我们再呆在这就要死了 赶紧
If we stick around here, we're dead. Come on!
我们得让所有人离开平台
We got to get everyone off this rig.
马上就来
Right behind you.
好了 救生船就在这里
Okay. Lifeboats are through here.
你准备好船 我把员工带来
You prep the boats-- I'll bring the crew to you.
好的
Okay.
快来
Come on.
Johnny 你得把吊车挪走
Johnny, you got to move this crane.
Benny有拖船要过来
Benny's got a tug coming in.
你们不能就这么随心所欲地踏进我的地盘
Hey, you can't just come onto my property anytime you want.
我们有搜查证就可以了
Got a warrant that says we can.
你所有的设施都归我们管
Your whole facility is under our control.
我们查了你的流水账单
We checked your revenue streams.
你关掉5号钻井平台 你的竞争对手有利可得
When you shut down rig 5, your competitors benefited,
但猜猜看谁的收益最大
but guess whose earnings went up the most?
你付钱给你的人 让他们在你的输油管凿洞
You paid your own men to put holes in your own pipeline,
阻断石油 拉高油价
choke out the oil, raise the prices of gas.
还导致一名无辜的海员在这一过程中丧命
And got an innocent sailor killed in the process.
我一个字都不用听
I don't have to listen to a word of this.
我要给我的律师打电话
I'm calling my lawyers.
哦 不必了 有人在你的办公室控制着
Oh, no, you're not. Someone in your office is controlling
钻取平台的压力系统
the pressure systems of the rig.
我们知道是谁了
And we're finding out who.
你们根本没有证据
You don't have a shred of evidence.
平台上的三个油井修建工就可以让你完蛋
We got three roughnecks on that rig that are ready to bury you.
所以你想炸掉它
Which is why you're trying to blow it up.
如果你不想一辈子待在监狱
If you want to avoid a lifetime in prison,
你就得告诉我们如何阻止这事情发生
you need to tell us how to stop this from happening.
我做的一切都是为了发展我的事业
All I've ever done is try to grow my business,
照顾我的员工
look out for my people.
为了救这些人我可以放弃一切
I'd give up everything to save those men out there.
我对这起事故没有责任
I'm not responsible for this catastrophe.
好吧 如果不是你 那会是谁 一名技工吗
Okay. If not you, then who, a technician?
他们必须得知道密码才能超控系统
They'd have to know the passcodes to override the system.
只有一个人...
Only one person...
我的天啊
God help me.
我的儿子
My son.
他是我们的首席技术官 是他设计的系统
He's our CTO, designed the system himself.
只有他了
He's the only one.
他人现在在哪儿
Where is he now?
不太舒服 说是得了流感 回家了
Didn't feel well. Said he had the flu, went home.
更可能是去机场了 我发协查通告去
More like the airport. I'll put a BOLO out.
我把一切都交给了他
I gave him everything.
你们得帮我阻止这事
You have to help me stop this.
好消息和坏消息 Patton恢复了和平台的通讯
Good news and bad-- Patton reestablished comms with the rig
中断了正在注入油井的泥浆
and shut off the mud being pumped into the well.
坏消息呢
And the bad?
这事情已经没办法回头了
This thing is past the point of no return,
不论是谁干扰它
and whoever was messing with it
都会使防喷器失灵
disabled the blowout preventer, too.
撤离倒计时已经开始了
Evacuation countdown's already begun.
我们离爆炸还有15分钟
We got 15 minutes before it goes up.
有可能保住它吗
Any way to save it?
有 奇迹
Yeah. A miracle.
或者是一个智商160的机械天才
Or a mechanical genius with an IQ of 160.
让Patton发我钻井平台的设计图 让我临时接入
Have Patton send me the rig blueprints and get me patched in out there.
我马上去拿电脑
I'm gonna be on a computer in two shakes.
该死的 Lund
Damn it, Lund!
你就是控制不住自己 是吗
You just can't help yourself, can you?
-情况紧急 -我管不了了
- It's an emergency! - I don't care!
你要是想拿到徽章 你就得听我的
You want a badge, you belong to me.
没有紧急情况 没有解释
No emergencies, no exceptions.
而且你也不能接触电脑 你听明白了吗
And no way you're going to those computers. You got it?
不 我没明白 因为如果要在我的团队和我的徽章中做选择
No, I don't get it. Because if it's a choice between my team
那我百分百选我的团队
or my badge, then I'm gonna choose my team every time.
现在 他们需要我
And right now, they need me.
你们跑不了了
You got no more moves,
Pride探员
Agent Pride!
出来吧
Come on out!
我们来谈谈
We'll conversate.
可以 只要你丢掉武器
It's a deal. Soon as you drop
向我们投降就可以了
your weapons and surrender.
该投降的不是我
I'm not the one who has to surrender.
我把你逼到了角落
And I've got you cornered.
你走投无路了
No way out.
他说得对 我们完蛋了
He's right. We're screwed.
你为什么这样看着我
Why are you looking at me like that?
你没有幽闭恐惧症 对吗
You're not claustrophobic, are you?
什么
What?
这真的不是个好主意
This is a really bad idea.
我甚至都不知道通风系统通往哪里
I don't even know where the ventilation system leads to.
会带你离开这里 这是肯定的
Out of here. That's for sure.
听着 你沿着这个通风口走 直到碰到第二个
Listen, you follow this vent until you find another one.
到食堂 把船员带到救生艇上
Get to the mess hall and get the crew to the lifeboats.
我们重新连上了
We're back online.
喂
Hello?
找你的
It's for you.
Pride
Pride.
Pride 我是Sebastian 没时间寒暄了
Pride, it's Sebastian. No time for small talk,
但我想我有办法阻止钻井平台爆炸
but I think I got a way to stop the blowout on the rig.
-Sebastian 你是个大救星 -现在 你需要帮助
- Sebastian, you're a lifesaver. - Now, you're gonna need help,
找一些个头特别大 很强壮的工人
so grab some-some big, burly drill dudes
然后到地下室去
and get to the cellar deck.
我知道你的动向 你到那里
I'm tracking your movements. I'll call you
再打给你
when you get there.
你有11分钟
You got 11 minutes.
记得在训练中的那个探员吗 那第四个探员
Remember that agent-in-training, the fourth one?
他可能有办法阻止这场爆炸
He may have a way to stop this thing from blowing.
-好极了 我们该怎么办 -你有11分钟
- Great. What do we do? - You got 11 minutes
找到出口 把船员带离钻井平台
to get up that vent and get the crew off the rig.
你不上船吗
You're not coming on the boats?
听着 这玩意儿要爆炸了
Look, this thing blows up,
石油会流入海湾
oil coats the gulf again,
这对海岸将是致命的打击
it'll be a death blow to the coast.
-好 -我不会让这事情发生
- Okay. - I'm not letting that happen.
那是什么
What is that?
喷灯火焰
Torch.
没错
Yeah.
他们正在进来 快走
They're cutting their way in. Go now.
你一个人办不到
You can't do this alone.
我不是一个人
I'm not alone.
听着 我们都有自己的任务 Bonnie
Look, we all got to do our part, Bonnie.
你得保证船员安全 现在快走
You got to get this crew to safety. Now go.
你是个奇怪的家伙 Pride
You're a strange dude, Pride.
Hauser
Hauser,
听好了 关掉喷灯
listen up! Turn off the blowtorch!
我出来了
I'm comin' out.
现在你听清楚我说的每一个字
And you're gonna listen to every word I have to say.
我们为什么要这么做
And why exactly will we do that?
因为这个钻井平台在10分钟之后要爆炸了
'Cause this rig's gonna blow in the next ten minutes,
而我是唯一一个知道如何阻止爆炸的人
and I'm the only one who knows how to stop it.
我们听着呢
Well, you got our attention.
最好快点说
Better talk quick.
胡说八道 他在虚张声势 好让Bonnie逃走
This is a bunch of crap. He's bluffing so Bonnie can get away.
你们有比她更严重的问题需要去担心
You got bigger problems to worry about than her.
钻井平台马上要变成大火球了
This rig's goin' up in a fireball
如果我们不做点什么
if we don't do something about it.
如果这地方要爆炸 我们肯定能听到警报声啊
If this place were gonna blow, we'd be hearing sirens.
刷新一下你的电脑
Refresh your computer.
警报系统应该重新上线了
Warning system should come back online.
让你破坏输油管的人
Whoever you were working with
给你下了套
to sabotage the pipeline set you up.
他们现在要毁尸灭迹 包括你们三个
Looking to clean up their mess. You three included.
他没说错
He's right.
井底的压力值都爆表了
Bottom hole pressure's off the charts,
防喷器也失灵了 你能改成手控吗
and the preventer's offline. Can you override it?
这儿不行
Not from here.
我们 好像 只有9分钟了
We got, like, nine minutes!
我们得上救生船
We got to get to the lifeboats.
不行 Bonnie和船员把船开走了
No, Bonnie and the crew took 'em.
你们别无选择 只能帮我
You got no other option but to help me.
只是管道上的几个洞 不是吗
Just a couple holes in the pipeline, huh?
为我的家人去做
Do it for my family.
这不是你说的吗 Hauser
Isn't that what you said, Hauser?
不不 这是他的错
Uh-uh, this is his fault.
继续在我脸上晃你的枪
Keep waving that weapon in my face,
我先崩了你
I'll feed it to you.
你说你知道怎么停止爆炸
You said you know how to stop it?
带我去底层甲板 我会告诉你的
Get me to the cellar deck. I'll show you.
-Sebastian 你说吧 -好的
- Talk to me, Sebastian. - Okay,
你们所要做的是
all you guys need to do
激活爆炸防护器
is activate the blowout preventer...
用来封住管道
...to seal the pipe
并防止在水下爆炸
and prevent an underwater blowout.
这很简单 是吗
That's easy, right?
现在 有两个幸运儿要爬去
Now, two lucky contestants are gonna climb down
下面的爆炸防护器
to the blowout preventer.
Pride 下去的路挺长的
Pride, it's a long way down.
你最好快一点
You better hurry.
明白了
Got you.
走吧 Hauser
Let's go, Hauser.
在上面的人
You guys up on the top,
你们得等到他们上来之后
you have to wait until they surface
再关上舱口 锁住阀门
before you close the hatch, turn the valves,
然后封井 如果你不这么做 你们会害死他们的
and seal the well. If you don't, you're gonna kill them.
好的 Pride 我看见你在下面了
All right, Pride, I see you down there.
找两块控制面板
Look for two control panels.
一块蓝色的和一块黄色的
One blue and one yellow.
现在 这部分非常关键 你必须
Now, this part is super important. You have to turn
同时转动两把激活钥匙
the activation keys at the same time.
他们花太久时间了 我们不能等了
It's taking too long. We can't wait!
钟走到五的时候 我就转
That clock hits five, I'm doin' it.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
在钟走到零的时候
Then book it up the ladder
你们得爬上梯子
before the clock strikes zero.
我要这么干了 关舱门
I'm doin' it. Close the hatch.
好的 我同意你
Yeah. I'm with you!
他们快上来了
They're almost up!
别 千万别
Don't! Just-just wait!
他们来了 他们就在那里了
They're coming. They're right there.
伙计们 快点出来 你们有十秒钟
Get out of there, guys. You got ten seconds.
八秒
Eight seconds.
六秒
Six seconds.
好了 关舱门 关舱门
All right, close the hatch! Close the hatch!
我们关上了 按按钮
We're closed! Hit it!
我们没事了
We're clear.
所以 现在怎么样
So... what now?
我不得不逮捕你们
I have to arrest you
因为Nielsen上尉的命案
for the murder of Lieutenant Nielsen.
你打算怎么做
And how do you plan to do that?
举起手来 混账
Hands up, jackass.
就是这样
That's how.
应该拿着那把枪的
Probably should've held on to that gun.
你回来了
You're back, huh?
每个人都要完成他们的任务
Everybody's got to do their part.
我的还没做完
Mine wasn't over.
好吧 我欠你的
Well, I owe you one.
让我和这些白痴们待五分钟 我们就扯平了
Give me five minutes with these morons, we'll call it even.
Lund
Lund.
我有话跟你说
I'm gonna tell you something.
不 是我有话跟你说
No, you know what, I'm gonna tell you something.
没错 我没有遵守命令
Yeah, I disobeyed a direct order.
但你知道吗 我不在乎
But guess what, I don't give a damn.
如果成为一名探员意味着
If becoming an agent means abandoning my team
在我的队伍需要我的时候抛弃他们
when they need me the most, well,
那你可以拿走我的徽章 并且你可以
then you can take that badge and you can sh...
Lund
Lund!
你做得很好
You did good.
再说一次
Come again?
还记得我让你爬绳子的时候 跟你说的话吗
Remember what I told you when I chased you up the rope?
我需要找到我向上的动力
That I needed to find a way to motivate my butt up it?
你愿意为了你的队伍放弃徽章
You were willing to sacrifice your badge for your team.
你找到了
You found it.
训练颇有成效 不是吗
Training works good, doesn't it?
现在回到训练房去 你给我
Now get back to the gym. You owe me
跑五十圈 因为违反规则
50 laps for breaking the rules.
长官 是的长官
Sir, yes, sir.
快点
Move it!
仅仅是管道上的几个洞
It was just a couple holes in the pipeline.
最终演变成海军军官的谋杀案
Which turned into the murder of a Navy officer
以及对24名钻机工人的谋杀未遂
and the attempted murder of 24 of your rig workers.
本应该没有人受到伤害的
No one was supposed to get hurt.
好吧 大家不都这么说
Well, that's what they all say.
我本意是让公司顺利运转
I was trying to keep the company afloat.
在这过程中差点毁了整个海湾
And nearly destroyed the entire Gulf in the process.
想象一下这会对你母亲产生什么样的后果
Imagine what that would've done to your mama.
我一辈子都在让她失望
I've disappointed her every day of my life.
我唯一想要的就是她对我的尊重
And all I ever wanted was her respect.
本以为如果我挽救了她宝贵的公司 我会获得尊重
Thought if I saved her precious company, I-I'd finally get it.
我向你保证一件事情
Well, I'll promise you one thing,
Angola的监狱顾问会给你足够多的时间
you'll have plenty of time to work through those mommy issues
解决你的恋母情结
with the prison counselor at Angola.
我会给国土安全部打电话
I'll call DHS,
让他们来接他去审讯
have them pick him up for processing.
Gregorio
Gregorio.
你干得非常棒
You did good in there.
谢谢
Thanks.
你也不赖
You weren't so bad yourself.
Roy 给我们一些时间好吗
Roy, will... you give us a minute?
嘿 Lasalle
Hey, look, Lasalle,
我知道我们一直合不太来 但今天是
I know we've been butting heads but today was like...
巨大的成功
A huge success.
都过去了
It was.
毕竟 我们最终抓到了坏人
I mean, after all, we took down the bad guys,
一天下来
and at the end of the day,
这才是最重要的事情 对吗
that's all that really matters, right?
是的 但我们还是因意见不合而大吵特吵
Right, but still, we were at each other's throats.
这是成长的烦恼 自古都是如此
It's growing pains, ancient history.
历史总是不断的重复
History tends to repeat itself.
就我看来
As far as I'm concerned,
因为我们都在乎 所以才吵架
we were arguing 'cause we both cared,
这是件好事情
and that's a good thing.
好吧 我同意
All right, I'm down with that.
但 还是发生了
Still, it happened.
所以 我们应该告诉Pride这血淋淋的细节 还是怎样
So, you think we can spare Pride the gory details, or what?
这只是办公室的日常
It's just another day at the office down here.
底线是
Bottom line,
他不需要知道今天发生的所有事情
is he doesn't need to know anything about today.
-哈喽 有人在家吗 -嘿
- Hello? Anybody home? - Hey!
-嘿 -他来了
- Hey, man! - There he is!
真高兴看你完好无缺的回来了
Hey, good to see you in one piece.
你是完好无缺的吧
You are in one piece?
当然 就一些小伤口
Oh, yeah, it's just a flesh wound.
如果不是你们的话 会糟糕很多
Could've been a lot worse if it hadn't been for you all.
我不在 你们干的不错
You did a good job without me.
哦 是的
Oh, yeah.
完全没有问题 就像上了油
This was seamless. It was like a well-oiled
但又很吵的机器
but extremely loud machine.
我需要知道这话什么意思吗
Do I want to know what that means?
意思是 我们很高兴看到你回来
It means we're glad to have you back,
主持大局
calling the shots.
好的 那这样
Okay. In that case,
我们先把文书工作放一边 去喝一杯吧
I say we forget the paperwork, go get a drink.
哦
Oh!
棒 正合我意
Yes. Now you're talkin' my language.
第一轮我买单
First round's on me.
恐怕我不能让你这么做
I'm afraid I can't let you do that.
这是我作为绅士的责任
It's my gentlemanly responsibility.
你这么说话真是
Literally makes me nauseous
令我恶心
when you talk like that.
他们一直这样吗
They been like this the whole time?
-别提了 -别提了
- You have no idea. - You have no idea.